Charles C. Carter

Information Technology and Data Analytics Professional

2315 Edgewood Road • Columbus, Georgia 31906 (706) 662-6351 • ccc31807@yahoo.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ccc31807 • https://github.com/ccc31807

ABOUT

Database, software engineering, and data analytics professional with extensive experience in database and web application development.. Language proficiencies: Python | C# | R | Perl | C. Database proficiencies: SQL Server | SQLite | PostgreSQL | MySQL. Master of Science: Applied Computer Science | Software Engineering | ABD in Software Engineering.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Candidate (ABD), Software Engineering Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama

Master of Science Candidate (15 hours completed), Analytics Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, Georgia

Master of Science, Software Engineering Auburn University, Auburn, Alabama

Master of Science, Applied Computer Science Columbus State University, Columbus, Georgia

Bachelor of Arts, History Mercer University, Macon, Georgia

no degree, Mathematics Columbus State University, Columbus, Georgia

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

February 2022 to current

Hexaware Technologies, Suite 600, 101 Wood Avenue S., Iselin, NJ 08830

- Python Developer
- Assigned to FNMA

Instructor (full time)

May 2017 to July, 2021

Embry Riddle Aeronautical University,

Fort Benning, Georgia 31905

Marine Base Quantico, Virginia 22134

- Instructor, Microsoft Software and Systems Academy
- Cloud Application Development
- T-SQL, SQL Server, SQL fundamentals
- $\bullet\,$ Programming in C#, program development and design
- ASP.NET, developing cloud applications
- Azure, Microsoft SQL Database, Azure application development

Adjunct Instructor (part time employment) Various terms from 2000 to current Columbus State University, 4225 University Ave, Columbus, GA, 31907 Columbus Technical College, 928 Manchester Expy, Columbus, GA, 31904 Missouri Baptist University, One College Park Dr, Saint Louis, MO 63141-8698

- Operating Systems (language: C)
- $\bullet\,$ Programming (languages: Python, JavaScript, Perl, C++)
- Software Engineering
- Advanced Database
- Computer Literacy and Productivity Apps

Quantitative Analyst

Dec 2014 to October, 2015

Synovus Bank,

33 West 11th Street, Columbus, Georgia 31901

- developed reproducible research automation with knitr and LATEX 2ε
- developed mapping applications with ggmap, choroplethr, and other R packages
- assisted in the development of automated data cleaning
- assisted in SDLC activities (SRS, BRD, FRD, and design documents)
- Primarily used R, SQL Server

Database Manager

Nov 2004 to Nov 2014

Troy University, 506 Manchester Expressway, Suite B20, Columbus, Georgia, 31904

- automated enrollment, registration, and term processes
- $\bullet\,$ developed and maintained systems for reporting and analysis of academic data
- · developed and administered databases supporting critical university functions
- implemented applications and programs as needed to support university needs
- Primarily used Perl, SQL Server, PostgreSQL

System administrator, developer

Jan 2001 to Dec 2013 (part time)

CFGroup.

2315 Edgewood Road, Columbus, Georgia, 31904

- administered HTTP (Apache) and database servers (MySQL)
- administered operating systems (SunOS and Linux)
- developed database driven web applications
- Primarily used Perl, bash, MySQL

Student, graduate assistant

May 2002 to May 2004

Columbus State University, 4225 University Avenue, Columbus, Georgia, 31907

- supervised student labs and tutored students
- administered Computer Science departmental servers (Linux, LinuxSE, FreeBSD)

Instructor

Jan 2000 to May 2002

Columbus Technical College, 928 Manchester Expressway, Columbus, Georgia, 31904

- taught Web Development curriculum (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, etc.)
- taught computer literacy, web development, and programming languages
- administered web servers for web program (FreeBSD and Linux)
- Primarily used Perl, JavaScript, C++

TECHNICAL CERTIFI-CATIONS

Cybersecurity Graduate Certificate(Currently in progress)

Google Data Analytics Certificate TSQL Querying (Exam # 70-761)

Infomation Security Professional CNSS/NSA4011

UNIX/Linux System Administration Windows 2000 Network Administration

Web Site Design

Signal Officer Basic Course

Columbus State University, Columbus, GA

Google LLC

Microsoft Corporation

Auburn University, Auburn, AL

Dekalb Technical College, Decatur, GA

Columbus Technical College, Columbus, GA

Columbus Technical College, Columbus, GA

U. S. Army Signal Corps, Fort Gordon, GA

TECHNICAL PROFICIEN-CIES

- Programming Languages: Python, C#, R, Perl, C, Octave, Common Lisp
- RDBMS: SQL Server, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Visualization Software: Tibco Spotfire
- Operating systems: Linux, Solaris, FreeBSD, Windows 2000
- Web Scripting Technologies: HTML, CSS, XML, XSLT, JavaScript
- Cloud Platforms: Azure, AWS
- Office Applications: Word, Excel, Access, PowerPoint, Outlook
- Other: Vim (vi), LATEX $2_{\mathcal{E}},$ graphviz, dia, git & Github

COMMUNITY SERVICE

- Columbus (Ga.) Data Science Meetup
- Taught programming courses for the Columbus home school association
- Tutored public school students in math
- Active in Gideons International
- Piper, Mercer University Pipes and Drums